If you are an NRI and are taking out a health insurance
policy, do not make the mistake of paying the full premium.  There are
many insurance
companies that give you discounts on your premiums.
Reason being you are an NRI.
This is not your primary policy.
Chances are low that you will use it.
That's why insurance companies are giving you some
discounts.  So
today we will discuss the policies with NRI discount.
What are the policies?
What are Terms and Conditions and how do they work?
[Music]
Quick reminder before we start the video,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, do so so that
you get the right information at the right time.   Let's
move on to the video on NRI discount
policies.  So we are going to discuss three policies
where NRR discount
is available.  The first one is Neevapa Rees 3.0
from HDFC Ergo Optima Secure and ICICI
Labard Elevate.  Some discounts are available for NRIs in these three policies.
If NRIs talk basically from the definition point of
view.  NRI is a person of
Indian origin who is living outside India.  I am
settled there for work.  Are you
working there, doing a job
, doing business or
living there for a long time.  So they are counted as NRIs.
So
these discounts are available for both NRI and OCI.  Provided they are
settled outside India.  If all the
insured members
are settled outside India, then they
are eligible for discount in all the three policies.  As soon as
you convert from NRI to resident individual.
Suppose you move back to
India, then you will
not get this discount.  You will have to
intimate the insurance company and these
discounts will be removed from you.  This
is as long as you are an NRI,
you can enjoy this discount.  So
Neemupper Reshore 3.0 is available at 15% discount
as an NRI.  As soon as you select 'Are
All Insured Members NRI',
you will get a discount of 15% straight away
on the premium.  And you already know one more thing
that GST has been exempted
on policies.  The GST of 18% has been removed.
So 18% GST is being accepted
and on top of that there is an additional 15% discount, which means
you will pay 15% less premium than what a resident individual pays. In IV Bub
Rushur 3.0 and One More Iteration, you
can use this policy only in India.  The
claims in all three policies can be
used only in India.
Cannot be used outside India.  So whatever claim will be there will be
within India only.  That means, suppose
you need to get some plant treatment done or you
are visiting India and you
need hospitalization, then
you can use these three policies.   You
can enjoy discount if you
are an NRI.  The second policy is HDFC
Ergo Optima Secure, here
you get 40% discount as an NRI.
Meaning your premium is reduced by 40%.  But it comes
with a certain clause.  Its clause is that you can
see it on the screen.  The first clause is that
you have to declare that you
are an NRI.  You will have to provide all the documents
as NRI or OCI and you
should be settled outside India and
all the insured members in the
policy will be eligible for NRI discount only then.
HDFC's clause is that the
40% discount that they are giving you, in whichever year
you make a claim, you will have to return this 40% discount.
For example, if the
premium is ₹50,000 and after 40% discount the
premium becomes ₹30,000, then you
get a discount of ₹20,000 for one year.  I am
taking the example, I got a discount of ₹000.
Suppose no claim came in that year.
Next year you paid the premium again but
no claim came.
You paid the premium in the third year and had to make a claim.
You came to India and
took the claim.  So at the time of claim, the insurance
company will say that the discount you have taken is
for the third year only.  Not for the first or second year,
you can return it only for the third year
and claim it from the policy.  So
you will get back the discount of Rs 20,000
and whatever the claim amount is, you will get it up to the sum
insured.  And next year
you will continue to enjoy NRI discount.  You will continue to
enjoy these discounts as long as you are an NRI.  So, in the year
you make the claim, you will return this discount
amount to the insurance company
only for the first claim.  Gave it in the first claim.
After that, the insurance company will settle the
entire claim of that year, no matter how many multiple claims are received, to
HDFCR.  The
third company ICICI Lo LMB has
NRI Advantage as an add-on which you
can add if you fall in the NRI category.
Here you get a discount of
25% again with the same condition that you
can take treatment only in India.  There
is a clause here that you can avail this discount only for a maximum of 5 years.  If
you
apply this discount today, you
can enjoy this discount for a maximum of five years only.
After that it will be removed.  You will have to
pay the full premium.  And there are
some rules common in all three companies which I would
like to tell you.  First of all, it
is necessary for you to be an NRI or an OCI. To
avail this discount, you will have to provide
some documents for that like your
passport copies, entry-exit stamps, when did
you go, when did you return, when did you go out of the country again,
your OCI cards, if you
are an OCI, if visa is applicable there then
visa document will be required, your
employment proof can also be asked for, the
insurance company will
also ask for your income proof as per AML guidelines, in
which you can provide your bank statement,
your ITR.  You
can give your salary slips.  And along with this, you will also have to provide your
overseas address proof of the place where you are living.
These are mandatory documents.  You may also have to
fill some allowances.  Some
additional forms will have to be filled where
you will have to fill the forms as per FEMA and AML guidelines.
You will have to
give a declaration as an NRI.  Along with this
you will also have to provide Indian documents.
Those KYC documents which
appear normal.  Which is pan, base.  Which
bank are you making the payment from?  Payment should be
from your NRO account.  Only then will this
discount be available to you.  The moment
you
become RI from NRI, you have to
inform the insurance company.  Next year
onwards your premium will be
charged as per resident individual.   The
cover is available only in India.
Not available outside India.  Now let us
quickly see what is the comparison between these three companies
?  So in Nevapuer ESO 3.0, we will first talk about
sum insured.  What sum insured
is available.  Unlimited sum insured
is available in NMIBS 3.0.  There are
no restrictions.  You
can claim as much as you want.
Standalone videos of these three products
are also available.  If you are interested, you can
refer.  3.0's is different.
You will also get HDFC Ago Optima Secure.
ICIC Elevate is also available on our channel.
Links to all three are given below.  The
minimum sum assured in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure is ₹
5 lakh.  The maximum is Rs 2 crore.
ICICI LBAD Elevate also has the option of minimum sum assured of Rs 5 and
maximum unlimited.  You
can choose.  Talking about room rent
eligibility here, there are four variants in Re 3.0.
Classic, Select, Elite
and Black.  In Classic, you will get general watt
, in Select you will get twin
sharing room.  Single
private AC room will be available in Elite and there is
no room rent capping in Black.  You can also have sweets.  There is
no room rent capping at HDFCO Optima Secure.  You can opt for any
room.  ICIC Elevate offers a single private AC
room.  You can upgrade to higher category
room by choosing room modifier rider.   The
tenure that is available is the policy tenure.
Tenure of 1 2 3 4 5 years is available in Nivapass 3.0.  This means that if you
want to take a policy for four or five years at a time,
you can do so.  Some additional discounts are
available.
One year, two year and three year policies are available in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
And in ICICI LAD Elevate, options up to 1 2 3 4 5 years
are available.  Multi tenure
policies are available.  Let's talk about bonuses.
This bonus is basically a no claim bonus.   There is a
loyalty bonus.  If
you are continuing the policy with a company then some
bonuses are given to you.  So there is
no bonus in Neemupper Reader 3.0 as the sum
assured is unlimited.  So there
is no need for bonus.  Later, if we talk about HDFCO
Optima Secure, then there is Pay Plus
benefit here which is 50% of your sum assured
is enhanced as loyalty addition
next year and 100% the next year.
So if you have insurance of 50 lakhs from last year
then next year it will become 75 lakhs.
After that it will become 1 crore.  And then let's
talk about ICICI LBA Deliverate.  There
is a cumulative bonus of 20% which increases up
to 100%.  Suppose you took a policy of Rs 50 lakh,
next year it will become Rs 60, then Rs 70
and then up to 100%, it will reach Rs 1 crore
in 5 years.  And this will not reduce.  If you take
any claim then you can do it in HDFC as well as
ICICI Elevate.  And one more thing in HDFC,
your cover is counted 2X from day one.
If you have taken a policy of Rs 50 lakh from Lets, then
it will be double counted as Rs 1
crore from day one.  If you take Super Secure which
is a three year policy.  Its
detailed video is also available on our channel.  So three
times counts.  50 lakh policy
will be counted as 1.5 crore from day one.
Day Care Procedures.  So day care
procedures are covered in all three policies
up to some in one shot.  Ayush Hospitalization.
AYUSH hospitalization is available for Ayurveda,
Yoga, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy.  All
three
policies cover up to sum in Rs.
Military hospitalization means
hospitalization at home in two conditions.   There is
no bed available in the hospital or the
patient is critical.  Cannot be taken to the hospital.
So hospitalization at home
is also covered.  Up to sum insured in all three policies.
Refill benefit.  Refill
benefit basically means that if your sum
insured is exhausted, the insurance
company is giving you refill and
restoration on top of that.  Refill
benefit is not available in NEEPA and is also not required
as the option of unlimited sum insured
is available.
Restore benefit is available once a year in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
For same illness and different
illness.  You can claim for anything.
You can convert this into unlimited restore
by paying a nominal
premium.  Unlimited refill benefit is available in ICICI Low LBA Elevate.   The
cost of emergency road ambulance to the hospital is also covered.   The
Nib Reur 3.0 has
hospitalization covered at ₹2000 in Classic and Select and
actual cover will be covered in Elite and Black.  HDFCO
Optima Secure has S per actual and
ICICI Low LBA Elevate also has S per actual.
Emergency Air Ambulance is not available in the Classic and
Select plans except
in Eshur 3.0.  Available in White and Black,
up to 5 L.  HDFC Ago Optima
Secure is also available up to Rs 5 lakh.
In ici lmb elevate you can add through rider.  There
is no inbuilt feature.
You
can add rider on Annual Health Checkup Neevapa Rs 3.0.  Through this policy you can get your annual health
checkup and preventive health checkup done.
This feature is inbuilt in HDFC Ago.
You can claim next year onwards on renewal.  Maximum
goes up to ₹15,000.  ICICI LBAD also has a
cashless plan and you have to add a rider
and you can claim from day one.
Talk about wellness benefits.
Wellness benefits are basically that the
company is focusing on your wellness.
The healthier your lifestyle, the
healthier you live, the more discounts you
get at the time of renewal.  How are these tracks made
?  You have to download the application of these insurance companies.
Your wellness benefits and wellness points are
counted in that.  Let's
walk this number of steps daily.  The insurance
company will give you a discount on that basis at the
time of renewal.  So
this wellness benefit discount of up to 30%
is available in Rashor 3.0 at Neema.  This is called Live Healthy Benefit.
Not available in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
Up to 20% of your wellness benefit
is available with ICIC LBR Elevate.  For this you have to download IL Tech Care app.
In ICIC LBARD and
for Neevapa, Neevapa Health App has to be downloaded.
You can get reimbursed pre and post hospitalization expenses i.e. expenses incurred before going to the hospital and expenses incurred after hospitalization related to hospitalization.
Nivapa Reshore 3.0 has a pre-existing condition of 60 days.
Post is 180 days HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure is covered up to 60 days pre and 180 days
post ICC LB Deliver is covered up to 90 days pre and
180 days post.  E-
Consultation.  So in Nibupas 3.0 you have
unlimited e-consultation available and
second medical opinion is available once a
year for which the person is hospitalized.
E-consultation for 51 listed critical
illnesses.  This is your unlimited e-consultation covered in HDFC and Optima
Secure as well as ICSC Elevate.
Modern
Treatments Robotic Surgery.  Three Assure
3.0 has a
sublimit of ₹1 lakh in Classic and Select plans. There is no sublimit
in SLT and Black on modern treatments like robotic surgeries.
If you do
n't want any restrictions then Alt and
Black is the plan for you.  There is
no limit in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
Covered up to sum insured.  There
is no limit in ICC LBA Elevate either.  Covered up to sum
insured.  Non-payable items Consumable
items.  So in Neema Reshore 3.0
you can add Claim Safeguard Plus to cover
your non-payable items.  There are four lists in it.
All four Annexures 1 2 3 4 will be
covered.  HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure already includes the Protect benefit.
So non-payable items you are
covered.  In ICIC LMAT Elvet, you need to
add a claim protector to cover
your non-payable items.  OPD cover.  So
OPD cover in Nibupas 3.0 Well Consult
Plus you can add rider to cover your
OPD expenses.  HDFC Ago also has OPD
cover. You have Optima Well Being Rider which
you can take to cover your OPD
expenses.  And ICICI LBA has B Fit Rider
which you can avail to cover deductible.  So
deductible is basically an option which
reduces your premium.  In this,
you agree that you will bear a small amount
yourself from the policy before taking the claim.
Suppose you have
taken a deductible of Rs 25,000 and a claim of Rs 5 lakh comes, then
you will pay Rs 25,000.  The insurance
company will give Rs 4,75,000.  In return, the insurance
company will charge you a lower premium.
Will not charge full premium, will charge less.
So, the deductible option available in Neev Reshore 3.0 ranges from Rs
10,000 to Rs 5 lakh.
Deductible options ranging from ₹25,000 to ₹5 lakh are also
available in HDFCO Optima Secure.  This option is not available in ICICI LBA.
Venture Copayment
Copayment again to reduce your premium.
You say that I will share the claim
so that you can reduce my premium.
Suppose a claim of Rs 1 lakh comes and
20% has been taken, then you will pay 20%.  The
insurance company will pay 80%.  In return,
you will be charged lower premiums.  So
voluntary copayment is available in Niva Reshore 3.0.
Not available in HDFC Ergo and
is available in ICICI LBD Elevate as a
rider.  Next is maternity expenses.
Maternity expenses are not covered under IVF 3.0.
No payable.
You can add Parenthood Rider in HDFCO Optima Secure,
which will also
cover your maternity expenses.  Coverage up to Rs 50,000, Rs 1 lakh, Rs 1.5 lakh or Rs 2 lakh
is available.  Newborn baby
expenses will not be covered.
You will have to add the newborn baby within 91 days.
Maternity rider will also have to be taken in ICICI Low LMA Elevate.
Rider for newborn baby and vaccination expenses will have to be taken.
So here the waiting
period for maternity in HDFC and ICICI is about two
years.  If you want to reduce it then there is an
option of reduction in ICICI.
You will have to serve for two years in HDFC.  Global
cover.  So Global Cover Neeva esh 3.0 includes
borderless and borderless for specified
diseases covered as a rider.  You
can avail the rider if you
wish to make a claim outside India.  Not available in HDFC Ago.  There
is a separate policy called Global
Plus Policy, you can see that.
Worldwide cover is also available in ICICI LBA which you
can avail if you want to get the coverage.
Now let us talk about waiting
periods and how many policies have waiting periods.  The
initial waiting period is
30 days in all three policies.
You cannot get the plant treated for the first 30 days.   The
specific exclusion waiting period is
two years and slow-growing
illnesses are not covered.  All these three plans will not cover diseases like
stone, cataract, hernia,
piles, fibroids for two years.
So here
you have the option to reduce the waiting period for specific exclusions.
This option is available in Nivapa and ICICI Lombard.
Not in HDFC.  Then there are pre-existing
diseases.  Meaning, if there was any disease before taking the policy, then there are
some waiting
periods on it.  Now you
can also reduce these waiting periods by adding some riders.
But the waiting period is standard, the
waiting period for all three policies is three years.
Rider available in Neevapa.
You can reduce the waiting period for 145 pre-existing diseases
to zero.
Your conditions ABCD in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure which are
Asthma, BP, Cholesterol,
Diabetes.  You can bring these conditions on day one.
And ICC Lambar also has Jump
Start Rider so that you
can get these conditions ABCD conditions on Day One
by paying additional premium.  Now let us talk about
optional riders and whether there are
optional riders in the policy.  The
first optional rider in Niva Reshore 3.0 is
Cashback Plus.  You want to
get cashback, which means if you do not claim,
you will get some percentage back every year
which will come into the wallet of Neevapa Health App,
through which you can pay the renewal premium
and use it for many things.
Neevapa One is an exclusive app
where you get state of the art services
, exclusivity and dedicated
support.  A lot can be achieved through this app.
Elder One is for elderly people who are
insured in the policy.  Annual health
checkup is a preventive health checkup
that you can get done once a year.  Then
Heads Up offers a discount and
you get a guided consultation
from the Nima Bupa team, who will recommend the
hospital where you need to get hospitalized.
Otherwise there is
copayment.  Tier network is also the same concept.
If you go to the Preferred Partner Network, you will get a
discount
on the premium.  If tomorrow you go to the bid of that network
then co-payment is also applicable.  So these are both
discount riders.  Then PED
wait period modification.  You have to
reduce the waiting period for pre-existing diseases,
which are the 145 illnesses we talked about.
So they can choose.  If you want to take the Specific
Disease Waiting Period Modification
from two years to one year
or three years, then the
option is available.  Copayment option is available
which is voluntary.  Voluntary deductible
option is available.  Personal Accident Rider
is available for accidental death and
disability.  Hospital Cash Benefit:
Daily cash benefit is given to you according to the number of days you are hospitalized.
Over and above the hospital bill.  Then Claim
Safeguard Plus to cover your non-payable
items. Well Consult Plus for OPD.
Borderless worldwide coverage and
borderless for specified illnesses.
Your Unlimited
Restore Benefit rider is available with HDFCO Optima Secure.
Hospital cash is available.  The IPA which we just talked about is
Individual Personal
Accidental Critical Illness Limitless
available.  Meaning, in which
you can claim any amount of your sum assured.  There are no
restrictions if you opt for Limitless Rider.  Then there's the
ABCD of chronic
care that we've been talking about to bring Day One PDS
and your parenthood for
maternity cover.  ICIC Elevate has a lot of
riders.  Let's talk about them.
Worldwide cover, treatment outside India
, chronic disease management
program, NRI advantage which we talked about
, NRI discount which you are getting
25% infinite care means whatever the
claim amount will be, the entire cover will be given.
Whatever your sum assured is.  Suppose you have a
sum assured of Rs 10 lakh and you have
taken Infinite Care and your claim comes to Rs
1 crore, then the company will give you the entire Rs 1 crore if you have this
rider.  Senior Care Value These are
added services.  Compassionate visit, two
hours hospitalization, all this is there in it.
Power booster, domestic air ambulance cover
is optional.  Jump start to cover your
ABCD conditions from day one which are
Asthma, BP, Cholesterol, Diabetes by
paying additional premium.  Dependent
Accommodation Benefit, Claim Protect,
Inflation Protector and much more.  You can
see it on the screen.  There are a lot of
riders.  You can check.  And if
you want to take a specific plan then
dedicated video is also available.  Detailed
video is also available.  They can also refer.
Because it is important to do your due
diligence and do a thorough research before buying
any health insurance policy.  And yes, if
you want to take a policy and
need guidance, you can also connect with our team.
Contact number email ID
is shared.  You can fill out a Google form.
Our team will connect you.  We Provide
Right Guidance, We Provide Right Product.
We provide onboarding services, complete
end-to-end services and specially claim
support.  If you need help with any claim,
our team will help you.  There
is dedicated claims support.  Now let us
move towards the premiums that how much premium
these premium policies will actually charge.
So I have written both with and without NRI
discount.  So that gives you a
reference line.  So
if we talk about premiums then we have taken the Niva ES 3.0 Black
variant which is the highest
variant which covers everything.  So
for unlimited sum insured, if the premium of zone one
without NRI discount is
33815,
with NRI discount it is 28743,
then all these premiums are without GST
because you know that GST has been exempted, you do
not have to pay GST. Now
if in HDFC, without NRI discount in Optima Secure it is
30813, with NRI discount
it is 18488, there is 40% discount but remember that
we have to give that discount back at the time
of claim. In ICICI Lo LBA the premium
is 20702, without NRI discount with NR
discount is 15526.
So these are age on date premiums.  These changes may happen
in the future.  These guidelines
related to NRIs can also change.  But when
we are making the video in September 2025.  So this
holds true.  So these were the
NRI discounted policy details from my side, if
you are an NRI and looking for health insurance
then these are the policies to go for.
Please do your due diligence before buying
any policy.  Want to connect I have
given you the contact numbers.  You
can connect.  And before we go, a quick
reminder, if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so.  So that
you get the right infection at the right time, see you
soon, stay safe and take care, bye-b